<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Xinyu Wu</title>
    <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Xinyu Wu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 19:31:51 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xinyuwu.xyz/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is This the Beginning of a New Era</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230324-beginning-of-a-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 19:31:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230324-beginning-of-a-new-era/</guid>
      <description>Looking back the past three decades of tech companies history, there were two big waves: web and mobile. Companies that thrived on web platform include names like Google, Amazon, Facebook, Linkedin, etc. Companies that started on mobile platform include Uber, Snapchat, Instagram, Tiktok, etc. Since Apple dominates the second wave, mobile platform, using its iOS app store, it has grown to be the largest company in the world.
It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 15 years since mobile platform started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Ability in the Era of chatGPT</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230312-ability-in-the-era-of-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 08:58:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230312-ability-in-the-era-of-gpt/</guid>
      <description>Since openAI release the GPT related model, more and more companies have integrated their services, including Microsoft (Bing), Notion, startups like Tome, etc. In the foreseeable future, the internet will be flooded with AI-generated (or partially generated) contents.
What’s more, since the model itself is trained on the data from the internet, it becomes a self reinforcing feedback loop. Any small issues will be magnified. Biased opinions, speculations, rumours, manipulative promotions will become common.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter, Mastodon and Nostr</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230220-twitter-mastodon-nostr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 12:37:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230220-twitter-mastodon-nostr/</guid>
      <description>Recently, there has been a lot of discussion regarding the problems with Twitter and the alternative platforms that aim to solve them. In this post, we will explore the main issues people have with Twitter and how its alternatives attempt to address these problems.
Twitter&amp;rsquo;s problems The primary issue with Twitter is censorship. As people increasingly rely on social networks like Twitter and Facebook for communication and news, Twitter has become a prominent platform for people to voice their opinions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
