<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Xinyu Wu</title>
    <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Xinyu Wu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:51:34 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xinyuwu.xyz/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20241119-bluesky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:51:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20241119-bluesky/</guid>
      <description>Recently a X competitor, Bluesky, has surpassed 20M users. They developed a new protocol called Authenticated Transfer Protocol (AT Protocol), aiming to solve the problems with X.
The problem with X  Centralized platform can ban users and all their history data cannot be recovered Centralized platform control the content moderation system (what can be shown, and how they will be shown in your timeline)  How Bluesky solve this problem  Bluesky is built on top of AT Protocol and multiple platforms can implement the same protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Innovator&#39;s Dilemma: A Startup&#39;s View</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20240826-innovators-dillema/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 19:03:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20240826-innovators-dillema/</guid>
      <description>Clayton M. Christensen&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Innovator&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma&amp;rdquo; explains why big companies fail at innovation despite their best efforts. Let&amp;rsquo;s apply this model to startups.
Startups often face the question: &amp;ldquo;What if a tech giant starts competing with you?&amp;rdquo; The common answer, &amp;ldquo;execution,&amp;rdquo; suggests startups can outpace established firms by iterating faster. This is true, but incomplete.
Startups creating disruptive technology have a key advantage: established competitors are captive to existing customers, finances, and culture within their value network &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;the context within which a firm identifies and responds to customers&amp;rsquo; needs, solves problems, procures input, reacts to competitors, and strives for profit&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StyleCraft</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20231009-style-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 18:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20231009-style-craft/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Element of Style&amp;rdquo; is a classic guide for writing non-fiction. The author emphasizes clear and concise writing to ensure readers can easily understand the writer&amp;rsquo;s ideas.
To write clearly, we must sharpen our writing skills. Writing well is a reflection of clear thinking. Beginners often struggle to improve without guidance from a professional writer who can show them how to write effectively and revise their work.
Gen AI has brought us the potential for an instant, effective teacher by our side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does USDC Work</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230913-how-does-usdc-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 19:33:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230913-how-does-usdc-work/</guid>
      <description>Fifteen years since the inception of the Bitcoin whitepaper, the search for concrete, real-world applications of blockchain technology continues. While the potential for Bitcoin to challenge the USD as the global settlement layer is still up for debate, stablecoins like USDC have emerged as a notable application. Given its prominence, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to discuss USDC&amp;rsquo;s mechanics, the challenges it addresses, and potential associated risks.
How Does USDC Work? The process of converting USD to USDC can be broken down into several steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Anxiety is Useless</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230328-ai-concerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:56:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230328-ai-concerns/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s only been a few months since chatGPT launched, but it&amp;rsquo;s quick to see people get into different &amp;ldquo;camp&amp;rdquo; on the future risk of AI. Earlier this week, there is an open letter signed by many top AI researchers and industry leaders to call for people to pause the research for next generation GPT and ponder on how we tackle the future risks. On the other side, howver, Yann LeCun is comparing this letter to Catholic Church&amp;rsquo;s moratorium of printing press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is This the Beginning of a New Era</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230324-beginning-of-a-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 19:31:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230324-beginning-of-a-new-era/</guid>
      <description>Looking back the past three decades of tech companies history, there were two big waves: web and mobile. Companies that thrived on web platform include names like Google, Amazon, Facebook, Linkedin, etc. Companies that started on mobile platform include Uber, Snapchat, Instagram, Tiktok, etc. Since Apple dominates the second wave, mobile platform, using its iOS app store, it has grown to be the largest company in the world.
It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 15 years since mobile platform started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Ability in the Era of chatGPT</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230312-ability-in-the-era-of-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 08:58:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230312-ability-in-the-era-of-gpt/</guid>
      <description>Since openAI release the GPT related model, more and more companies have integrated their services, including Microsoft (Bing), Notion, startups like Tome, etc. In the foreseeable future, the internet will be flooded with AI-generated (or partially generated) contents.
What’s more, since the model itself is trained on the data from the internet, it becomes a self reinforcing feedback loop. Any small issues will be magnified. Biased opinions, speculations, rumours, manipulative promotions will become common.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter, Mastodon and Nostr</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230220-twitter-mastodon-nostr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 12:37:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230220-twitter-mastodon-nostr/</guid>
      <description>Recently, there has been a lot of discussion regarding the problems with Twitter and the alternative platforms that aim to solve them. In this post, we will explore the main issues people have with Twitter and how its alternatives attempt to address these problems.
Twitter&amp;rsquo;s problems The primary issue with Twitter is censorship. As people increasingly rely on social networks like Twitter and Facebook for communication and news, Twitter has become a prominent platform for people to voice their opinions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
