<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>startup on Xinyu Wu</title>
    <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/tags/startup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in startup on Xinyu Wu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:51:34 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xinyuwu.xyz/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20241119-bluesky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:51:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20241119-bluesky/</guid>
      <description>Recently a X competitor, Bluesky, has surpassed 20M users. They developed a new protocol called Authenticated Transfer Protocol (AT Protocol), aiming to solve the problems with X.
The problem with X  Centralized platform can ban users and all their history data cannot be recovered Centralized platform control the content moderation system (what can be shown, and how they will be shown in your timeline)  How Bluesky solve this problem  Bluesky is built on top of AT Protocol and multiple platforms can implement the same protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Innovator&#39;s Dilemma: A Startup&#39;s View</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20240826-innovators-dillema/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 19:03:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20240826-innovators-dillema/</guid>
      <description>Clayton M. Christensen&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Innovator&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma&amp;rdquo; explains why big companies fail at innovation despite their best efforts. Let&amp;rsquo;s apply this model to startups.
Startups often face the question: &amp;ldquo;What if a tech giant starts competing with you?&amp;rdquo; The common answer, &amp;ldquo;execution,&amp;rdquo; suggests startups can outpace established firms by iterating faster. This is true, but incomplete.
Startups creating disruptive technology have a key advantage: established competitors are captive to existing customers, finances, and culture within their value network &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;the context within which a firm identifies and responds to customers&amp;rsquo; needs, solves problems, procures input, reacts to competitors, and strives for profit&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup: How To Come Up With Ideas</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230305-understanding-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 15:07:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230305-understanding-business/</guid>
      <description>I want to start a series of blog posts on startups. This is the first one. In this post I am going to use online ads business and a popular startup TripleWhale to talk about how to come up with ideas.
Starting From The Problem Understanding the Market Size From 10000 meters&amp;rsquo; view, people wants to sell stuff. This is oldest business since the beginning of human society. Now with the development of internet, lots of sales have moved to online, so called ecommerce.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
