<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Xinyu Wu</title>
    <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Xinyu Wu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 09:12:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understand Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230610-understand-consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 09:12:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230610-understand-consumerism/</guid>
      <description>This post is a review of Anthony Galluzzo&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;La fabrique du consommateur&amp;rdquo; (The making of the consumer).
The allure of consumerism lies in its premise that one can redefine oneself through consumption. In the infancy of capitalism, the aristocracy, the nascent bourgeoisie, and the lower classes coexisted. The aristocracy was recognized by their family name, which required no further validation. The lower classes focused more on production as a means of survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think Clearly (1): Cause and Effect</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230603-how-to-think-clearly-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 21:55:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230603-how-to-think-clearly-1/</guid>
      <description>We often read and hear people stating that A leads to B in life. People enjoy discussing causality, yet finding true causality can be challenging. Before we leap to hasty conclusions, we might benefit from asking ourselves a few simple questions to think clearly.
Is A a sufficient condition to B? Are there examples of A that do not lead to B? Some people may claim that the smaller the government is, the better the quality of life will be for its citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe&#39;s Lesson</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230527-europe-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 20:18:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230527-europe-lesson/</guid>
      <description>This post serves as a continuation of our previous discussion &amp;ldquo;Japan&amp;rsquo;s Lesson&amp;rdquo;. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into understanding the economy of Europe over the past two decades through the lens of balance sheet recessions.
To grasp the complexities of Europe&amp;rsquo;s economy, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand the mechanics of its monetary and fiscal policies. Countries within the Eurozone utilize the common currency - the Euro. The European Central Bank (ECB) was established to govern the monetary policies of Eurozone countries, which influence the interest rates on the Euro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan&#39;s Lesson</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230517-japan-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 18:36:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230517-japan-lesson/</guid>
      <description>This is a book review on Richard Koo&amp;rsquo;s The Holy Grail of Macroeconomics and The Escape from Balance Sheet Recession and the QE Trap.
The asset bubble in Japan crashed at the end of the 1980s and didn&amp;rsquo;t recover until the early 2010s, leaving behind many lessons for the world. This kind of recession is referred to in the book as a Balance Sheet Recession. Other examples of such recessions include The Great Depression of the late 1920s and The Great Recession of 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Cultivate a Long-Term Relationship: Admiring them for Who they Are</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230416-admire-them-for-who-they-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 19:22:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230416-admire-them-for-who-they-are/</guid>
      <description>Expressing appreciation genuinely and timely is a very important thing to do in a relationship. It is like water that should be part of your life. If anything is even more important, it’s admiration.
Let me put the take away message at the beginning: appreciate them for what they do and admire them for who they are.
Here are some examples on how to deliver admirations. They convey a more impactful message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future is Inherently Unpredictable</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230407-the-future-is-not-predictable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 20:48:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230407-the-future-is-not-predictable/</guid>
      <description>Scientific philosopher’s view Karl Popper once wrote in “The Logic of Scientific Discovery”: “The advance of scientific knowledge is not determined by any causality; it is rather to be conceived as a series of creative acts of imagination.” “Scientific hypotheses are never strictly deducible from the available data; they are always conjectures, which are tested by being subjected to critical scrutiny and refutation.” He emphasized the importance of empirical testing and the falsifiability of a scientific theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Cultivate a Long-Term Relationship: Spend Quality Time Together</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230405-spend-quality-time-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 23:32:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230405-spend-quality-time-together/</guid>
      <description>The secret to cultivating a long-term intimate relationship lies in intentionally spending quality time together.
Life is busy. We are all preoccupied with our work, logistics, chores, catching up with news. Merely being together is not enough because time together doesn’t necessarily convert to deep connection with our partner, or the feeling of intimacy, or rediscover life&amp;rsquo;s meaning. We must actively seeking moments of quality time together. Can&amp;rsquo;t find time? It’s simple: make time and prioritize it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Anxiety is Useless</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230328-ai-concerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:56:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230328-ai-concerns/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s only been a few months since chatGPT launched, but it&amp;rsquo;s quick to see people get into different &amp;ldquo;camp&amp;rdquo; on the future risk of AI. Earlier this week, there is an open letter signed by many top AI researchers and industry leaders to call for people to pause the research for next generation GPT and ponder on how we tackle the future risks. On the other side, howver, Yann LeCun is comparing this letter to Catholic Church&amp;rsquo;s moratorium of printing press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is This the Beginning of a New Era</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230324-beginning-of-a-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 19:31:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230324-beginning-of-a-new-era/</guid>
      <description>Looking back the past three decades of tech companies history, there were two big waves: web and mobile. Companies that thrived on web platform include names like Google, Amazon, Facebook, Linkedin, etc. Companies that started on mobile platform include Uber, Snapchat, Instagram, Tiktok, etc. Since Apple dominates the second wave, mobile platform, using its iOS app store, it has grown to be the largest company in the world.
It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 15 years since mobile platform started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomics 101: What will happen after printing money?</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230313-printing-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 07:10:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230313-printing-money/</guid>
      <description>We have always heard that printing money will cause inflation. Is that a universal truth? What other things could change because of it? This post tries to describe what could happen after the quantity of money in the market increases.
First of all, how does central banks influence money supply? They can do so through open market operations, which means purchasing financial securities (government bonds or other assets from private financial institutions) on the open market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Ability in the Era of chatGPT</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230312-ability-in-the-era-of-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 08:58:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230312-ability-in-the-era-of-gpt/</guid>
      <description>Since openAI release the GPT related model, more and more companies have integrated their services, including Microsoft (Bing), Notion, startups like Tome, etc. In the foreseeable future, the internet will be flooded with AI-generated (or partially generated) contents.
What’s more, since the model itself is trained on the data from the internet, it becomes a self reinforcing feedback loop. Any small issues will be magnified. Biased opinions, speculations, rumours, manipulative promotions will become common.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did SVB Fall</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230311-why-svb-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 09:52:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230311-why-svb-fail/</guid>
      <description>There are numerous news and posts covering Silicon Valley Bank situation. This post aims to explain the core of the issue in a clear question and answer way.
Q: Why did SVB Fall?
A: Because of bank run.
Q: How could bank run cause such a big problem in 2023? Aren&amp;rsquo;t banks FDIC insured?
A: FDIC insures up to $250000 of every deposit account. SVB has a unique business that services startups in Silicon Valley, so majority of its client has a number in their account much larger than $250000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career advice: should you work on making others like you?</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230310-should-you-make-others-like-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 07:18:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230310-should-you-make-others-like-you/</guid>
      <description>During the early days of my career, my mentor told me that one of the most important thing about working at a company is making other people like you. It’s important because it will make collaboration much easier. People are more likely to lend you resources during the project and give you credit after the project. In short, the more friends you have at the company, the more successful you will be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup: How To Come Up With Ideas</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230305-understanding-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 15:07:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230305-understanding-business/</guid>
      <description>I want to start a series of blog posts on startups. This is the first one. In this post I am going to use online ads business and a popular startup TripleWhale to talk about how to come up with ideas.
Starting From The Problem Understanding the Market Size From 10000 meters&amp;rsquo; view, people wants to sell stuff. This is oldest business since the beginning of human society. Now with the development of internet, lots of sales have moved to online, so called ecommerce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Spanish A1 Tenses Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230303-spanish-a1-grammar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 18:58:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230303-spanish-a1-grammar/</guid>
      <description>This is a blog post about Spanish A1 Tenses Cheat Sheet. Irregulars are not included in this post.
Present Tense Regular    Pronoun -AR -ER -IR     Yo Hablo Como Vivo   Tu Hablas Comes Vives   Él Habla Come Vive   Nosotros Hablamos Comemos Vivimos   Vosotros Habláis Coméis Vivís   Ellos Halan Comen Viven    Reflesive verbs:    Pronoun Reflexive Pronoun Verb     Yo Me Baño   Tu Te Bañas   Él Se Baña   Nosotros Nos Bañamos   Vosotros Os Bañais   Ellos Se Bañan    Verbs like Gustar    Optional Mandatory Verb     A mí Me Gusta(n)   A ti Te Gusta(n)   A él Le Gusta(n)   A nosotros Nos Gusta(n)   A vosotros Os Gusta(n)   A ellos Les Gusta(n)    Whether to use Gusta or Gustan depends on whether the word after it is plural or not</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Benefits From a Low Interest Rate</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230225-who-benefit-from-low-interest-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 20:13:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230225-who-benefit-from-low-interest-rate/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I watched a video online about interest rate. A comment under the video caught my eye:
 Rich people earn money from their interest-bearing savings. Poor people need to pay the debt interest. High interest rate increases wealth inequality. As a poor, I hope to live in the world of low interest rate.
 While I understand the rationale behind it, there might be another aspect to this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Buyback and Interest Rate</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230224-how-does-stock-buyback-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 19:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230224-how-does-stock-buyback-work/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays we have seen lots of news about companies buying back their stocks. For example, here is a stock buyback chart for Apple Inc in the past few years:
(source: YChart)
Usually after the stock buyback plan is announced, the company&amp;rsquo;s stock goes up. Why does a company buy back its stock? Why does the buyback push up the stock price? Why do we see the stock buyback happen more frequently in the past decade?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter, Mastodon and Nostr</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230220-twitter-mastodon-nostr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 12:37:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230220-twitter-mastodon-nostr/</guid>
      <description>Recently, there has been a lot of discussion regarding the problems with Twitter and the alternative platforms that aim to solve them. In this post, we will explore the main issues people have with Twitter and how its alternatives attempt to address these problems.
Twitter&amp;rsquo;s problems The primary issue with Twitter is censorship. As people increasingly rely on social networks like Twitter and Facebook for communication and news, Twitter has become a prominent platform for people to voice their opinions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Analytics to Your Website</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230219-how-to-add-analytics-to-your-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 16:17:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230219-how-to-add-analytics-to-your-website/</guid>
      <description>After you have your personal website ready, you might wonder how many people have visited your website and where they are. Here are the steps you need to add analytics to your website.
Step 1: Setup Google Analytics  Create an account at google analytics Go to Admin -&amp;gt; Property -&amp;gt; Property Settings to create a property Go to Admin -&amp;gt; Property -&amp;gt; Data Streams to create a stream  You will get a Google Tracking Code that looks like &amp;ldquo;G-XXXXXXXXXX&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Custom Domain For Your Github Page</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230219-how-to-add-custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 15:06:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230219-how-to-add-custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>Step 1: Buy a custom domain you like. You could use services like Godaddy.
Step 2: Add DNS record for your custom domain Add these 4 type A DNS record to point to github pages
Then add this type CNAME DNS record to point to your github pages
Then wait for the DNS to propagate. It could take from minutes up to 24 hours to propagate.
Step 3: Add custom domain in your Github Page repo Go to settings and select Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast</title>
      <link>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230217-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 18:48:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xinyuwu.xyz/blog/20230217-fast/</guid>
      <description>Being fast is the key to build something new. If you have a startup idea, build it within a weekend time. If you have a feature to launch, build it within one day. If you want to learn a new language, learn the most basic 200 words within 2 weeks and start using them. If you want to build a personal website, build it within one hour. If you want to write a blog, finish it within 30 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
